<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="app_name">AdaptKey</string>
    <string name="ime_name">AdaptKey</string>
    <string name="settings_title">AdaptKey Settings</string>
    <string name="subtype_de_qwertz">German (QWERTZ)</string>

    <!-- Suggestion bar drag-to-trash (G-04). -->
    <string name="suggestion_trash_label">🗑  Delete</string>

    <!-- D-247: the "Gelernt: X" confirmation chip and its own two-zone drag (shallow: unlearn only, deep:
         permanent blacklist). -->
    <string name="suggestion_learned_label">Learned: %1$s</string>
    <string name="suggestion_forget_label">Forget</string>
    <string name="suggestion_forbid_label">Forbid</string>

    <!-- Info & privacy category (shown first on the settings screen). -->
    <string name="cat_info">Info &amp; Privacy</string>
    <string name="info_privacy_title">No internet, no tracking</string>
    <string name="info_privacy_summary">This keyboard holds no internet permission — verifiable in the system. Nothing is "phoned home"; everything stays on the device.</string>
    <string name="info_license_title">Licence</string>
    <string name="info_license_summary">Free software: GPL-3.0-or-later. Copyright © 2026 Froehlich Media.</string>
    <string name="info_version_title">Version</string>

    <!-- D-89: full feature overview, listing everything AdaptKey does so nothing stays hidden. -->
    <string name="d89_title">What AdaptKey can do</string>
    <string name="d89_summary">AdaptKey records the exact raw touch position behind every letter you type, not just which key it resolved to, and continuously adjusts each key\'s own hit zone to your personal tap pattern - seeded from the typing style you chose during setup, then refined by every further keystroke.</string>
    <string name="d89_learn_more">Learn more</string>
    <string name="d89_f01_title">Adaptive touch model</string>
    <string name="d89_f01_desc">Learns your personal tap pattern for every key from everyday typing — an optional short calibration gives it an immediate head start, and it keeps refining itself afterwards.</string>
    <string name="d89_f02_title">Diacritic-aware autocorrect</string>
    <string name="d89_f02_desc">Missing diacritics (like German umlauts and ß) are restored automatically when unambiguous, or offered as the top suggestion otherwise — e.g. "konnen" → "können".</string>
    <string name="d89_f03_title">Neighbour-key and space correction</string>
    <string name="d89_f03_desc">Fixes typos landing on an adjacent key and repairs a missed or an accidentally inserted space between two words.</string>
    <string name="d89_f04_title">Undo an autocorrection</string>
    <string name="d89_f04_desc">A single backspace tap right after an autocorrection restores exactly what you typed, instead of just deleting a letter.</string>
    <string name="d89_f05_title">Multi-alternative long-press popup</string>
    <string name="d89_f05_desc">Long-press any key that has more than one alternative to choose from all of them at once, Gboard-style.</string>
    <string name="d89_f06_title">Alt-key symbol hints</string>
    <string name="d89_f06_desc">Common symbols (@, €, #, π, ×, ÷ and more) sit as long-press hints directly on letter keys, so you rarely need to leave the letter page.</string>
    <string name="d89_f07_title">Persistent number row</string>
    <string name="d89_f07_desc">Digits stay on a row of their own above the letters, each with its shifted symbol one long-press away; switch it off in settings if you prefer.</string>
    <string name="d89_f08_title">Swipe between letters and symbols</string>
    <string name="d89_f08_desc">A left/right swipe anywhere on the keys cycles through the letter page and both symbol pages — no need to reach for the small "?123" key.</string>
    <string name="d89_f09_title">Space-bar language switch</string>
    <string name="d89_f09_desc">Swipe left or right on the space bar to switch which language you\'re typing in.</string>
    <string name="d89_f10_title">Swipe to delete a whole word</string>
    <string name="d89_f10_desc">Swipe left on the backspace key to delete the entire previous word in one motion.</string>
    <string name="d89_f11_title">Swipe down to dismiss</string>
    <string name="d89_f11_desc">Swipe downward anywhere on the keyboard to hide it.</string>
    <string name="d89_f12_title">Drag a suggestion to the trash</string>
    <string name="d89_f12_desc">Drag a suggestion up into the trash area that appears to permanently exclude it — a deliberate motion, so it never happens by accident.</string>
    <string name="d89_f13_title">Retroactive capitalisation</string>
    <string name="d89_f13_desc">Press Shift right after finishing a word to flip the case of its first letter — or, if you keep typing, the next letter is capitalised instead (handy for camelCase).</string>
    <string name="d89_f14_title">Quick paste from the clipboard</string>
    <string name="d89_f14_desc">Clipboard content appears where the suggestion bar normally is; tap it to paste. Passwords are masked, and the clipboard is cleared right after pasting.</string>
    <string name="d89_f15_title">Next-word prediction</string>
    <string name="d89_f15_desc">The suggestion bar predicts a likely next word before you\'ve typed a single letter of it.</string>
    <string name="d89_f16_title">Optional on-device mini-AI</string>
    <string name="d89_f16_desc">A small language model can be downloaded once and imported to sharpen suggestions further — it runs entirely on the device, so the offline guarantee never changes.</string>
    <string name="d89_f17_title">Three languages, detected automatically</string>
    <string name="d89_f17_desc">German, English and Greek each have their own dictionary; the active one is detected automatically from what you\'re actually writing.</string>
    <string name="d89_f18_title">Provably offline</string>
    <string name="d89_f18_desc">This keyboard requests no internet permission at all — check it yourself in the system\'s app settings.</string>

    <string name="d89_f19_title">Remembers your usernames and emails</string>
    <string name="d89_f19_desc">Recognises login fields and offers your own previously used usernames and email addresses as you type. Every saved value can be reviewed or removed from settings any time, or saving can be switched off entirely — passwords are never touched or recorded, no matter what.</string>
    <string name="d89_f20_title">Suggest emails from your contacts</string>
    <string name="d89_f20_desc">An optional, opt-in setting offers email addresses from your address book alongside your saved ones — permission is asked for right there in settings, never behind your back.</string>
    <string name="d89_f21_title">Dedicated keyboard for URL and email fields</string>
    <string name="d89_f21_desc">A web address or email field automatically gets its own keyboard row (https://, www., a dedicated @ or slash) — switchable back to the ordinary keyboard from the extra row if you just want to search or type normally.</string>
    <string name="d89_f22_title">Review what the keyboard has learned</string>
    <string name="d89_f22_desc">See every word AdaptKey has taught itself from your own typing, kept completely separate from the built-in dictionary, and remove any of them individually.</string>
    <string name="d89_f23_title">Password manager suggestions</string>
    <string name="d89_f23_desc">Autofill suggestions from your password manager appear right in the suggestion bar when available.</string>
    <string name="d89_f24_title">Recognises unhyphenated compounds</string>
    <string name="d89_f24_desc">Long compound words are recognised and corrected even without a hyphen, from their known component parts.</string>
    <string name="d89_f25_title">Suggests the missing space in run-together words</string>
    <string name="d89_f25_desc">Two words typed without a space in between are offered back apart, as a normal suggestion-bar tap.</string>
    <string name="d89_f26_title">Swipe up for the extra row</string>
    <string name="d89_f26_desc">An upward swipe on the keyboard reveals a row of extra actions — emoji panel, clearing the clipboard, and a live view of your personal touch-zone model.</string>

    <!-- Settings screen (C-01 … C-09). -->
    <string name="cat_layout">Layout &amp; Keys</string>
    <string name="cat_suggestions">Suggestions</string>
    <string name="cat_dictionary">Dictionary</string>
    <string name="cat_capitalisation">Capitalisation</string>

    <string name="c01_space_title">Space bar width</string>
    <string name="c01_space_summary">Narrower reduces accidental spaces instead of commas (L-02).</string>
    <string name="c01_comma_title">Comma width</string>
    <string name="c01_period_title">Full-stop width</string>
    <string name="c01_backspace_title">Extra backspace width</string>
    <string name="c01_backspace_summary">Percentage surcharge, taken from the neighbouring keys (L-04).</string>
    <string name="c01_shift_title">Extra shift width</string>
    <string name="c01_shift_summary">Percentage surcharge for the shift key (D-16). Preset by calibration; adjustable.</string>

    <string name="d234_autocorrect_enabled_title">Autocorrect</string>
    <string name="d234_autocorrect_enabled_summary">Corrections, diacritic restoration, and missed-space fixes apply automatically while typing. Turn off to keep every candidate available only as a tap in the suggestion bar - words are never silently changed, but a missed or spurious space is not corrected either.</string>
    <string name="c02_title">Re-sort delay</string>
    <string name="c02_summary">Pause without input after which the suggestion bar re-sorts (0–600 ms).</string>
    <string name="c03_title">Maximum suggestions</string>
    <string name="c03_summary">Number of simultaneously stabilised suggestions (6–10).</string>
    <string name="c04_enabled_title">Word confirmation highlight</string>
    <string name="c04_enabled_summary">Highlights a recognised, complete word while typing (S-05).</string>
    <string name="c04_color_title">Highlight colour</string>

    <string name="c09_title">Number row</string>
    <string name="c09_summary">Persistent digit row above the letters (L-06).</string>
    <string name="d32_title">Long-press delay</string>
    <string name="d32_summary">How long to hold a key before its alternatives pop up, in ms (D-32).</string>
    <string name="d59_title">\?123/ABC key</string>
    <string name="d59_summary">Show the combined ?123 key. With this off, the key disappears and its slot stays empty (D-59).</string>
    <string name="d55_below_title">Space below number row</string>
    <string name="d55_below_summary">Extra gap under the digits, in dp, to reduce mis-taps into the top letter row (D-55).</string>
    <string name="d55_above_title">Space above space bar</string>
    <string name="d55_above_summary">Extra gap above the space/enter row, in dp, to reduce accidental Enter presses (D-55).</string>
    <string name="c08_hints_title">Show corner symbols</string>
    <string name="c08_hints_summary">Secondary long-press symbols as a corner hint (L-05). Long-press still works either way.</string>
    <string name="c08_reset_title">Reset corner symbols</string>
    <string name="c08_reset_summary">Resets the per-key assignment to the default mapping.</string>
    <string name="c08_reset_done">Corner symbols reset to default.</string>
    <string name="c08_editor_title">Edit corner symbols</string>
    <string name="c08_editor_summary">Set or remove a secondary symbol per letter (L-05).</string>
    <string name="c08_editor_intro">Tap a letter to choose or remove its long-press symbol.</string>
    <string name="c08_editor_none">— no symbol —</string>

    <string name="c05_title">Edit blacklist</string>
    <string name="c05_summary">Permanently exclude words from suggestions and autocorrect (A-04).</string>

    <string name="d177_learned_words_title">Learned words</string>
    <string name="d177_learned_words_summary">Review or remove words the keyboard has taught itself from your own typing - including ones that never show up as a suggestion.</string>

    <string name="d177_expiry_title">Forgotten-word memory</string>
    <string name="d177_expiry_summary">How long a removed learned word is remembered before it can quietly be learned again (1–30 days).</string>

    <string name="d142_credentials_title">Saved usernames &amp; emails</string>
    <string name="d142_credentials_summary">Review saved login values, remove one at a time, or clear them all.</string>

    <string name="d224_save_credentials_title">Save credentials</string>
    <string name="d224_save_credentials_summary">Recognised usernames and email addresses are saved for later suggestion. Never affects passwords - those are never recorded regardless of this setting. Already-saved values keep being suggested either way.</string>

    <string name="d191_contacts_suggestions_title">Suggest contacts\' emails</string>
    <string name="d191_contacts_suggestions_summary">Offers email addresses from your address book alongside your saved credentials, once allowed. Your contacts are read live and never stored in this app. Turning this on asks for the Contacts permission once, right here.</string>
    <string name="d191_contacts_permission_denied">Contacts permission not granted - suggestions from contacts stay off.</string>

    <string name="c07_title">Shift grace window</string>
    <string name="c07_summary">Guards against surprising field capitalisation (0–500 ms).</string>

    <string name="c10_title">No sentence start after a comma line</string>
    <string name="c10_summary">After a line ending with a comma (e.g. a mail salutation), the next line is not capitalised.</string>

    <string name="c06_title">LLM threshold</string>
    <string name="c06_summary">The n-gram confidence below which the mini-LLM is consulted (C-06). The LLM backend is not wired in yet.</string>
    <string name="c06_threshold_low">Low</string>
    <string name="c06_threshold_medium">Medium</string>
    <string name="c06_threshold_high">High</string>

    <!-- C-06 tier-3 model management (browser download + file import). -->
    <string name="c06_model_pref_title">Mini-LLM model (tier 3)</string>
    <string name="c06_model_pref_summary">Download and import the optional on-device model (C-06).</string>
    <string name="d126_title">Mini-LLM enabled</string>
    <string name="d126_summary">When off, the mini-LLM never runs, even if a model is installed - useful to save battery/latency without deleting the model.</string>
    <string name="c06_model_title">Mini-LLM model</string>
    <string name="c06_model_intro">The tier-3 mini-LLM (C-06) is optional. The model (~273 MB) is not bundled in the app. Download it once and then import it — afterwards the app keeps working fully offline.</string>
    <string name="c06_model_present">Model installed.</string>
    <string name="c06_model_absent">No model installed. Tier 3 is inactive; the keyboard works as usual.</string>
    <string name="c06_model_download">1. Download the model (in the browser)</string>
    <string name="c06_model_import">2. Import the downloaded file</string>
    <string name="c06_model_remove">Remove model</string>
    <string name="c06_model_importing">Importing model …</string>
    <string name="c06_model_imported">Model imported.</string>
    <string name="c06_model_import_failed">Import failed.</string>
    <string name="c06_model_removed">Model removed.</string>
    <string name="c06_model_no_browser">No browser found. Please download and import the file manually.</string>
    <string name="c06_model_privacy">This app holds no internet and no storage permission. The download runs through your browser; the app only reads the one file you pick.</string>

    <!-- First-run onboarding (shown above the keyboard). -->
    <string name="onboarding_step_indicator">Step %1$d / %2$d</string>
    <string name="onboarding_next">Next</string>
    <string name="onboarding_finish">Done</string>
    <string name="onboarding_skip">Skip</string>
    <string name="onboarding_welcome_title">Welcome to AdaptKey</string>
    <string name="onboarding_welcome_body">AdaptKey learns how YOU type — and stays completely offline while doing so.\n\n• Provably offline: no internet permission at all — you can check it in the system. Nothing is ever "phoned home", and there is no tracking.\n• Reads your actual taps, not just your typing: it remembers exactly where each tap really lands, so it can recover a word even when a slip landed on the wrong key entirely — not just a neighbouring letter. A short calibration gets it right from the start.\n• Smart correction: fixes typos on neighbouring keys and missing accents (e.g. "komplezz" → "komplett"), and repairs missed or accidental spaces.\n• Learns gently over time: suggestions and autocorrect keep improving, but only from a steady pattern — a single mistake never throws a key off.\n• Three languages: German, English and Greek, each with its own dictionary.\n• Optional on-device mini-AI for even better suggestions — downloaded once, still no internet.\n• Free software (GPLv3), no ads, no accounts.</string>
    <string name="onboarding_model_title">Optional mini-AI</string>
    <string name="onboarding_model_body">Optionally, a small AI (mini-LLM) can improve the suggestions when the normal model is unsure — entirely on the device. The model (~273 MB) is not included: you download it once via the browser and import it. Afterwards everything stays offline. You can skip this now and add it any time later.</string>
    <string name="onboarding_model_action">Set up model</string>
    <string name="onboarding_calibration_title">How do you type?</string>
    <string name="onboarding_calibration_body">Finally, tell AdaptKey how you usually type. It sets up realistic touch zones for your fingers right away, then keeps refining them gently as you type. Optional and changeable any time later.</string>
    <string name="onboarding_calibration_action">Set typing style</string>
    <string name="onboarding_footer_hint">You can reach this introduction any time via Settings → Info &amp; Privacy → "Show introduction again".</string>
    <string name="onboarding_replay_title">Show introduction again</string>
    <string name="onboarding_replay_summary">Shows the first-run introduction again the next time you open the keyboard.</string>
    <string name="onboarding_replay_done">The introduction will be shown the next time you open the keyboard.</string>

    <!-- Reset learned touch data (offset model T-03 + typing style T-04), double-confirmed. -->
    <string name="reset_learning_title">Reset touch calibration</string>
    <string name="reset_learning_summary">Resets your learned touch zones back to the defaults for your current typing style - not the style itself, and not the dictionary.</string>
    <string name="reset_learning_confirm1_message">Your learned touch zones will be reset to the defaults for your current typing style. Continue?</string>
    <string name="reset_learning_confirm2_title">Reset permanently?</string>
    <string name="reset_learning_confirm2_message">This step cannot be undone.</string>
    <string name="reset_learning_done">Touch calibration reset.</string>
    <string name="k01_reset_button">Reset calibration</string>

    <!-- D-142: clear the saved usernames/email addresses (a separate store, never the dictionary). -->
    <string name="d142_clear_credentials_title">Clear saved usernames &amp; emails</string>
    <string name="d142_clear_credentials_confirm_message">Every saved username and email address will be deleted. This cannot be undone. Continue?</string>
    <string name="d142_clear_credentials_done">Saved usernames &amp; emails cleared.</string>

    <!-- Typing style detection (T-04). -->
    <string name="t04_pattern_left_index">Left index finger</string>
    <string name="t04_pattern_right_index">Right index finger</string>
    <string name="t04_pattern_left_thumb">Left thumb</string>
    <string name="t04_pattern_right_thumb">Right thumb</string>
    <string name="t04_pattern_two_thumbs">Both thumbs</string>
    <string name="t04_pattern_unknown">Not set yet</string>

    <!-- Calibration / onboarding (K-01). -->
    <string name="cat_calibration">Calibration (K-01)</string>
    <string name="k01_title">Typing style</string>
    <string name="k01_summary">Tell AdaptKey how you type, so key detection fits you from the start (K-01).</string>
    <string name="k01_current_style">Currently: %1$s</string>
    <string name="k01_activity_title">Typing style</string>
    <string name="k01_intro">How do you usually type? This sets up realistic touch zones for your fingers right away; ordinary typing keeps refining them gently from there.</string>
    <string name="k01_skip">Skip</string>
    <string name="k01_switch_confirm_title">Switch typing style?</string>
    <string name="k01_switch_confirm_message">Touch calibration resets to sensible defaults for %1$s. Continue?</string>
    <string name="k01_switch_done">Typing style updated.</string>
    <string name="k01_offer_title">Set your typing style?</string>
    <string name="k01_offer_message">Would you like to tell AdaptKey how you type? It sets up realistic touch zones right away. You can do this any time in the settings.</string>
    <string name="k01_offer_start">Set it now</string>
    <string name="k01_offer_later">Later</string>

    <!-- Blacklist editor (C-05). -->
    <string name="blacklist_title">Blacklist</string>
    <string name="blacklist_language">Language:</string>
    <string name="blacklist_word_hint">Word</string>
    <string name="blacklist_add">Add</string>
    <string name="blacklist_empty">No entries.</string>
    <string name="blacklist_removed">%1$s removed.</string>
    <string name="blacklist_remove_confirm_title">Remove “%1$s” from the blacklist?</string>
    <string name="blacklist_remove_confirm_action">Remove</string>
    <!-- D-206: bundled entries are rarely of interest and should rarely be removed, so the list starts
         filtered to user-added entries only; this reveals the bundled ones too. -->
    <string name="blacklist_show_bundled">Show built-in entries too</string>

    <!-- Learned-words editor (D-177). -->
    <string name="learned_words_title">Learned Words</string>
    <string name="learned_words_language">Language:</string>
    <string name="learned_words_empty">No learned words yet.</string>
    <string name="learned_words_removed">%1$s forgotten.</string>
    <string name="learned_words_remove_confirm_title">Forget “%1$s”?</string>
    <string name="learned_words_remove_confirm_action">Forget</string>

    <!-- Saved usernames/emails editor (D-180). -->
    <string name="credentials_empty">No saved usernames or emails yet.</string>
    <string name="credentials_removed">%1$s removed.</string>
    <string name="credentials_remove_confirm_title">Remove “%1$s”?</string>
    <string name="credentials_remove_confirm_action">Remove</string>

    <!-- Shared "copy to clipboard" option on the blacklist / learned-words / credentials remove dialogs. -->
    <string name="copy_to_clipboard_action">Copy</string>
    <string name="copy_to_clipboard_done">%1$s copied to clipboard.</string>

    <!-- Key-press feedback (D-05 / D-06). -->
    <string name="cat_feedback">Key-press feedback</string>
    <string name="d05_sound_title">Key sound</string>
    <string name="d05_sound_summary">Plays a short click on every key press (default: off).</string>
    <string name="d06_haptics_title">Vibration</string>
    <string name="d06_haptics_summary">A short vibration on every key press (default: off).</string>

    <!-- Touch-pattern visualisation (D-24). -->
    <string name="d24_intro_1">The coloured circles show where your key taps land on average (the dot) and how much they scatter (the circle).</string>
    <string name="d24_intro_2">This is how the keyboard adapts to your typing.</string>
    <string name="d24_empty">Nothing learned yet. Type for a while or start the calibration.</string>

    <!-- D-139/D-110: in-memory diagnostic log, an alternative to adb logcat that needs no PC/USB tether. -->
    <string name="cat_diagnostics">Diagnostics</string>
    <string name="d_diag_enabled_title">Record diagnostic log</string>
    <string name="d_diag_enabled_summary">Keeps a rolling 1-minute, in-memory log of recent typing events to help track down rare glitches. Off by default, and never written to disk or sent anywhere unless you explicitly share it below. Password fields are always excluded, regardless of this setting.</string>
    <string name="d_diag_log_title">View / share diagnostic log</string>
    <string name="d_diag_log_summary">Shows the current log and lets you copy or share it.</string>
    <string name="d_diag_activity_title">Diagnostic log</string>
    <string name="d_diag_empty">No entries yet. Turn on recording in Settings, reproduce the issue, then come back here within 5 minutes.</string>
    <string name="d_diag_share">Share</string>
    <string name="d_diag_copy">Copy</string>
    <string name="d_diag_clear">Clear</string>
    <string name="d_diag_copied">Copied to clipboard.</string>
    <string name="d_diag_cleared">Log cleared.</string>
</resources>
